Zhijiang Rongliang Wuxian Technology (Zhejiang) Co., Ltd. Zhejiang Yanhe Culture Technology Co., Ltd.
This is the official document.
We suspect you killed Musician Han
and his senior disciple Cui Yujing.
We're here to investigate.
You still won't give up.
Feel free to look around.
Two great detectives,
did you find
Gu insects,
medicinal powder,
or other murder weapons?
There is nothing.
That should be right.
You memorized it so fast.
Look.
This is the score for 'Nanshan Youtai'.
The Shang note here
has been changed to the Yu note,
and the rhythm is half a beat slower.
This seemingly minor adjustment
perfectly matches the evil melody 'Chonggu Yao'.
I'll go catch him right now.
Wait.
Ashina Xiao
didn't have any prior contact
with the deceased.
Someone else did the poisoning.
The person in this lute academy
who helped him poison
and alter the score
is the real mastermind.
We need to play the long game,
so don't alert the enemy.
You have a smart brain.
So smart.
He's back.
Help!
There's a ghost!
He's back.
Help!
He's back! There's a ghost!
There's a ghost!
I was wrong.
Spare me!
What's wrong with you?
I'm young and ignorant.
Don't kill me. I know I was wrong.
Make him stop.
Stop!
Spare me!
Are you okay?
Lord Su.
What happened?
We were on duty last night,
and heard someone calling for help.
And then we saw...
a dark figure playing a zither.
The sound of it killed him.
Is that yellow wine?
It's the Jiuyin Gu again.
What about Ashina Xiao?
Following your orders,
our men
kept an eye on Ashina Xiao all night.
He never left the inn.
Then who could it be?
Oh, right.
Before he died,
he kept saying...
I was still young then.
I didn't know any better.
Spare me!
He kept shouting this.
Lord Su,
it sounds like
he was talking to his classmate.
Did they do something wrong
to him back then?
Could it be that
Chu Feng has returned?
Ghosts killing people?
Don't let your imagination run wild.
Chu Feng died long ago.
There's no such thing as ghosts.
There were two of you.
How could you not even catch
a shadow playing the zither?
Although I didn't catch the shadow,
I cut this off from him.
This is silk.
According to the laws of the Tang Dynasty,
only officials of the third rank and above can wear silk.
Oh my.
Our magistrate is only of the sixth rank.
Prince Ling's Mansion.
We are ordered to investigate the murders
of Cui Yujing and Musician Han.
I would like to ask you
to help identify something.
This fabric
belongs to the royal court.
The material, pattern, and style all match.
May I ask, Princess,
have any stewards or servants gone missing
from your mansion recently?
Or
are any items missing?
No.
I haven't seen Prince Ling.
Prince Ling is very busy.
Even your magistrate has to report in advance
if he wants to see him.
So you won't be able to see him.
Does Lord Su suspect
that last night's murder
is related to Prince Ling's Mansion?
You know about last night's incident, Princess?
Fangzhou is only so big.
News of someone dying on the street spreads fast.
Lord Su,
this fabric is indeed rare among the common people,
but it is common in our court.
There are so many royal mansions in the Tang Dynasty.
How can you be sure
that this fabric is from Prince Ling's Mansion?
I would like to look around the mansion,
if I may?
Of course.
Lord Su,
this is the record of all fabric purchases
in Prince Ling's Mansion.
Indeed, nothing is missing.
Look.
This guy likes reading as much as you do.
Indeed.
See?
I told you this has nothing to do
with Prince Ling.
Not necessarily.
I noticed that many books in the study
are on parchment from the Western Regions.
Is there anything strange about that?
Prince Ling was originally the Crown Prince,
but was demoted to Fangzhou.
Do you think he harbors resentment?
Does he have a motive
to use the Zither Demon and Gu poison
to cause chaos in Fangzhou
and take revenge on the imperial court?
I think Prince Ling is a nice person.
Are you overthinking?
Think about it.
Prince Ling was just demoted to Fangzhou not long ago,
and now strange cases are happening one after another here.
Although the cases are independent,
there might be a conspiracy
that we don't know about hidden within them.
What conspiracy could Prince Ling possibly have?
I don't know.
I'm just guessing.
Your Highness has been staying up late a lot recently.
Have some snow fungus porridge.
Princess,
are you sure this piece of fabric
is not from our mansion?
I checked the recent entry and exit records of Fangzhou,
and there is no one from Chang'an.
This fabric
indeed comes from the Prince Ling Mansion.
What?
Then why didn't you
tell Su Yao?
This concerns a murder case.
How could I say it?
Don't forget
that so many people in Chang'an have their eyes on you.
If someone finds out
and causes trouble,
what will we do?
Your Highness, don't worry.
Let me solve the case.
You
can solve cases?
Do you remember a few years ago
at your birthday banquet,
some court musicians came to perform?
You were so impressed at the time
that you rewarded each musician
with a bolt of ice silk brocade.
Well,
I really don't remember that.
This is the roster of the musicians you rewarded back then.
I remember that year,
the male musicians received navy blue,
and the female musicians received ink black.
Female musicians?
There were only two female musicians at the time.
One was a pipa player from Liangzhou,
and the other
was a guqin player from the Chang'an Qin Academy.
It's her,
Chu Xiaoxiao.